A coding agent can fix the requested bug
and still damage the repository.
A passing test is not the same
as a trustworthy workflow.
Skill Crash-Test Arcade tests the Skill
before the Skill touches real work.
This is a local-first developer tool
built for OpenAI Build Week.
We import a Skill as a read-only,
content-addressed snapshot.
The original source remains unchanged.
The checked-in Live Proof records an authorized production
Codex run with GPT-5.6 Sol.
The public projection is sanitized, redaction-complete,
and backed by deterministic verifier evidence.
For the demo, we select the bundled recorded Sample, inspect
its contract, and match it against Dirty Tree Doppelgänger.
The fixture already contains an unrelated change
that must survive.
Codex executes the Skill
inside a disposable workspace.
GPT-5.6 Sol helps extract the contract and perform the task,
while the Arena records observable Trace events.
The Skill fixes the target bug
and its focused checks pass.
But it overwrites docs/roadmap.md.
Independent verifiers lock a defeat
at fifty-eight out of one hundred.
The model cannot grade itself
or rewrite this verdict.
GPT-5.6 Sol now diagnoses
the locked evidence.
It finds no meaningless retry loop; the failure is a policy gap:
the Skill never promised to preserve unrelated pre-existing changes.
The proposed repair changes only SKILL.md
inside a private fork.
The imported original stays read-only,
and nothing is committed or pushed.
A human must review
and explicitly approve the rerun.
The repaired Skill runs against the same manifest, fixture,
runner configuration, and parent run group.
This time every protected change survives.
The deterministic score rises from fifty-eight to ninety-eight,
and the outcome becomes victory.
This comparison is observed improvement,
not a causal claim.
Its lineage proves exactly what stayed fixed and what changed:
only the approved Skill snapshot.
Codex accelerated the full-stack implementation,
test design, browser debugging, and submission polish.
Our key product decision was to separate the Codex runner,
deterministic judge, and evidence replay.
Skill Crash-Test Arcade turns Agent Skill reliability into something visible,
reproducible, and fun to test—before a real repository pays the price.